The happiest sound in all the world!
The Sound of Music is a drama, family, music film directed by Robert Wise.
In the years before World War II, a tomboyish postulant at an Austrian abbey is hired as a governess in the home of
a widowed naval captain with seven children and brings a new love of life and music into the home.
Maria, played by Julie Andrews.
Captain Georg von Trapp, played by Christopher Plummer.
The Baroness, played by Eleanor Parker.
Liesl von Trapp, played by Charmian Carr.
Friedrich von Trapp, played by Nicholas Hammond.
Louisa von Trapp, played by Heather Menzies.
The Sound of Music  is a 1965 American musical drama film produced and
directed by Robert Wise from a screenplay written by Ernest Lehman.
It is based on the 1959 stage musical composed by Richard Rodgers, with lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein II and a book by
Lindsay and Crouse, itself based on the 1949 memoir The Story of the Trapp Family Singers by Maria von Trapp.
The film stars Julie Andrews and Christopher Plummer, with Richard
Haydn, Peggy Wood, Charmian Carr, and Eleanor Parker.
Set in Salzburg, Austria, it is a fictional retelling of Maria von Trapp's experiences as governess to seven children, her
eventual marriage with their father Captain Georg von Trapp, and their escape during the Anschluss in 1938.
Filming took place from March to September 1964 in Los Angeles and Salzburg.
The Sound of Music was released by 20th Century Fox in the United States on
March 2, 1965, at first as a limited roadshow theatrical release.
It initially received mixed reviews from film critics.
However, the film was a major commercial success, becoming the number-one box
office film after four weeks, and the highest-grossing film of 1965.
By November 1966, The Sound of Music had become the highest-grossing film in history,
surpassing Gone with the Wind, and it held that distinction for five years.
The film was popular throughout the world, breaking
previous box-office records in 29 countries.
The Sound of Music had an initial theatrical release that lasted
four and a half years, and two successful re-releases.
It sold 283 million admissions worldwide and earned a
total worldwide gross of $286 million.
The Sound of Music received five Academy Awards,
including Best Picture and Best Director.
The film also received Golden Globe Awards for Best Motion Picture and Best Actress, the Directors Guild of America Award for
Outstanding Directorial Achievement, and the Writers Guild of America Award for Best Written American Musical.
Since its original release, the film is widely regarded
as one of the greatest films of all time.
In 1998, the American Film Institute (AFI) listed The Sound of Music as the 55th
greatest American film of all time, and the fourth-greatest film musical.
In 2001, the United States Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the National
Film Registry, finding it "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of resistance, musical, austria,
based on true story, music competition.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.